Tead, Ordway Papers 5530
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Ordway Tead Papers
1935-1994
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Tead, Ordway
5530
18 cubic feet
18 linear ft.
Papers (documents), manuscripts (documents), correspondence.
Approximately 250 in number, manuscripts range in form from notes, to unedited and edited drafts of articles, to addresses. They cover a wide range of topics in the fields of business management, public administration, and higher education.
3121086
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, January 20, 2016
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 18, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Ordway Tead (b.1891-d.1973) was an administrator, teacher, editor, and profilic author. The papers document the interrelations of theory and practice in business management, public administration, and higher education. Tead is the author of twenty-one books and numerous articles on economics, history and education. He was a civil libertarian and an advocate of equal rights for women.
Scope and Contents
Manuscripts.
Approximately 250 in number, manuscripts range in form from notes, to unedited and edited drafts of articles, to addresses. They cover a wide range of topics in the fields of business management, public administration, and higher education. Major subjects of Tead's writings include: faculty administration; personnel administration; educational administration; church administration; personnel management; industry leadership; executive leadership; collective bargaining; liberal education; higher education; labor-management relations; education; faith; religion; democracy; industrial conflict; industrial relations; women and education; college teaching; human values; teachers; administrative personality; human relations; and two-year colleges. Tead's early manuscripts also include poetry and eleven play scripts, of which two are "Teaching Teddy: A Satire On Politics," and "The Professor at the Luncheon Table, or the Dictagraphs Revenge."
Correspondence.
Spanning from 1965 to 1969 (carbons and originals), this material is of a professional and personal nature. The professional correspondence deals chiefly with Tead's involvement in the publishing industry as an editor for the McGraw-Hill Book Company, and as an editor and director of social and economic books for Harper and Brothers. Major correspondents include: Oliver C. Carmichael (Ford Foundation Consultant), Thomas L. Cheney (Lawyer), Henry Geiger (Publisher, MANAS), John Graves, Richard H. Guggenheimer, John M. Gaus, Louis Finkelstein (Conference on Science, Philosophy, and Religion), Clara Fraser, M.J. Holahan (Secretary, Scholarship and Education Committee of Pitney-Bowes, Inc.), Gerhard Hirschfeld (Executive Director, Council for the Study of Mankind), Helen Emmans Hoar, Marvin T. Judy (Southern Methodist University), Robert L. Jackson (Yale University), John E. Ivey, Jr. (Dean, Michigan State University), F.L. Kunz (The Foundation for Integrative Education, Inc.), Irene R. Kiernan (Fashion Institute of Technology), Douglas M. Knight (President, Duke University), Allan Lewis (Director, The Shakespeare Institute), A.A. Liveright (Boston University), Charles T. Laugher (Amherst College), Howard Lee Nostrand (University of Washington), Thomas C. Mendenhall (President, Smith College), H.B. Maynard (President, Maynard Research Council), Franklin Patterson (President, Hampshire College), Earl V. Pullias (University of Southern California), Edward Joseph Shoben, Jr. (Director, American Council of Education), James H. Shroder, Evelyn Buckley Sauer (Management Consultant), Herbert Stroup (Brooklyn College), Henry W. Sweeney (Deputy Assistant, Secretary of Defense), Phil Tead (brother), Doris Campbell Thomas (Long Island University, C.W. Post College), Sherwood Trask, Mrs. Richard (Marguerite) Tirk, Robert Ulrich, Oliver L. Reiser (University of Pittsburgh), Herbert Coslet Armstrong, John J. Carhart, Thomas Dreier, and Clarence A. Faulcon. Also included is letter (1969) from Pitney-Bowes scholarship recipients to Tead on his retirement from the scholarship board; and letters (1965-1968) acknowledging receipt of contributions (gift and monetary) by Tead to various institutions and associations.
Clippings and reviews.
Clippings include articles on and by Tead;.the reviews deal with Tead's published books College Teaching and College Learning (1949), The Case of Democracy (1937), Human Nature and Management (1933), The Climate of Learning (1958), The Art of Administration (1951), and Character Building and Higher Education (1953); there are also reviews (1920-1927) written by Tead. Also included are reprints of Tead's publications.
Publications, reprints, and correspondence of Tead's colleagues.
Includes material by and about Abraham H. Maslow (Brandeis University), Ross Mooney (Ohio State University), Lewis Munford, Gardner Murphy, Oliver L. Reiser, E. John Wallace (Society for the Advancement of Management), Marshall Demock (University of Colorado), E.D. Duryen (Syracuse University), Frederick de W. Bolman, Delmer Goode (Oregon State University), and Robert G. Valentine.
Materials documenting Tead's work with the Bureau of Industrial Research
This portion of the collection includes: one volume (carbon) of Labor Survey of the Tanning Industry made for the Labor Committee of the Tanner's Council of America (1918); one volume (carbon) of the Industrial Audit of the Rock Island Arsenal with special reference to the principal sources of dissatisfaction, by Valentine, Tead and Gregg (Industrial Counselors); one volume (carbon) Industrial Audit of Osborn Mills, Fall River, Massachusets, by Valentine, Tead and Gregg; and series of data gathering forms designed and copywrighted (1916) by Valentine, Tead, and Gregg.
Miscellaneous materials
Included are: syllabi outlines and examinations for courses taught by Tead at Briancliff College, two recording tapes concerning an unidentified institute at which Tead spoke (1965); and 212-page (carbon) "Reminiscences of Ordway Tead" by the Oral History Research Office of Columbia University (1961).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Industrial relations -- United States -- Sources; Tead, Ordway, 1891-1973
3121086
- Ordway Tead, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Personal (Current and Recent), 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 50th Wedding Anniversary (Included verse by O.T.), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- -Y-, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- -W-, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Misc., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- -P-, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- -T-, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- -S-, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- -V-, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- -U-, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- -N-, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- -L-, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- -M-, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- -O-, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- -K-, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- -J-, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- -G-, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- -H-, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- -F-, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- -G-, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- -C-, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Pamphlets of Maslow's Writings (Box 2, Folder 13)
- First Half of June 1965 Institute (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Film - Recording Acetate Tape
- Second Half of June 1965 Institute (Box 2, Folder 2)
- 10 Years of Closed Circuit TV at Stephens College, 1955-1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Stephens College House Plan, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Ordway Tead, 1915-1918 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Picture
  - Item 1: Woman Munitions Worker, 1918; Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Woman operating a machine, possibly loading cartridges, at the Frankford Arsenal, March 27, 1918.
- Articles by Ordway Tead [folder 1 of 3], 1928; Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 6a)
- Articles by Ordway Tead [folder 2 of 3], 1928; Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 6b)
- Articles by Ordway Tead [folder 3 of 3], 1928; Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 6c)
- Articles by Ordway Tead, 1929-1937; Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Tead Articles 1938 [folder 1 of 3], Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 8a)
- Tead Articles 1938 [folder 2 of 3], Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 8b)
- Tead Articles 1938 [folder 3 of 3], Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 8c)
- Briar Cliff Chapel Talk, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Bargaining Ordway Tead, 1935; Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Ordway Tead [folder 1 of 5], 1950-1951; Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 11a)
- Ordway Tead [folder 2 of 5], 1950-1951; Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 11b)
- Ordway Tead [folder 3 of 5], 1950-1951; Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 11c)
- Ordway Tead [folder 4 of 5], 1950-1951; Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 11d)
- Ordway Tead [folder 5 of 5], 1950-1951; Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 11e)
- Pamphlets by Abraham H. Maslow, 1949-1963; Black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Ordway Tead, 1965; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Ordway Tead, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Ordway Tead, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Ordway Tead, 1969; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Ordway Tead, 1954-1955; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Ordway Tead, 1954; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Ordway Tead, 1954-1955; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Reviews of O. Teads, 1951; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Mooney, Prof. Ross L., 1967; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Mumford, Lewis, 1943; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Gardner Murphy, 1953; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Columbiau - Oral History - OT, 1970; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Reiser, Oliver L., 1966; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Ordway Tead, 1957-1958; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Ordway Tead, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Ordway Tead, 1964-1966; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Ordway Tead, 1965; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Ordway Tead, 1965; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Ordway Tead, 1965; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Ordway Tead, 1965; Black and white photograph (Box 3, Folder 20)
- O. Tead - Autobiography, 1968; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 1)
- The Executive's Reading, Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 2)
- The Ethical Challenge of Modern Administration, 1960; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Freedom and Conformity in Industrial Leadership, 1953; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Human Relations in Management West Penn Power Co. - Jan 1958, Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Human Relations in Management (West Penn Power Co - 1958), Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Industrial Relations and the Public, Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Perspective on Democratic Industrial Government, 1942; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Labor Management Relations and The Public Interest, 1948; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Is Industrial Self-Government Possible?, Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Leadership Emphasis in Administration, 1953; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 11)
- New Directions in Collegiate Business Education, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Personnel Administration - Today and Tomorrow (Amer Tel and Tel - 4/27/55), 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Reflections on the Art of Administration, 1966; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Reflections on the Art of Administration, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Reviews by Ordway Tead, 1957-1958; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Ordway Tead, Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Tomorrow's Administrative Personality, Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 18)
- What is Executive Leadership (US Public Health Service), 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 19)
- "Youth and the Labor Unions", 1937; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Maslow Prof. A.H., Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Hawaii Includes Wallace Correspondence, 1965; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Book Reviews by Ordway Tead (2), 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Ordway Tead, 1927; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 24)
- What Faith Will Make Men Whole? (Washington), 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Miscellaneous, Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Ordway Tead, 1964; Black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Ordway Tead, 1960-1970; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Ordway Tead, 1915; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Armstrong, Prof. Hubert C., 1965; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Biography - O. Tead, 1918-1945; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Board of Higher Education City of New York, 1964-1965; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Book Reviews By Ordway Tead (1), 1966; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Carhart, John J., 1965; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Contributions Reported for 1966, Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Dimock, Sr. Marshall E., 1965-1966; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Duryea, Prof. E. D., 1965; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Drier, Thomas, 1965; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Faulcon, Clarence A., 1966; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Foundations in Education (Company Sponsored, 1965; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Goode, Prof. Delmer M., 1965; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Ordway Tead, 1969-1970; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Tax Exempt Donations 1968, Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 16)
- About O.T., 1919; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 17)
- By O.T., 1920-1922; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Business Cycles XVII - Courses, Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Ordway Tead, 1927-1929; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 20)
- By O.T., 1923-1927; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Ordway Tead, 1969; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Real Correspondence, 1968-1970; Black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Ordway Tead, Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Faith: Toward the Wholeness of Man, Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Ordway Tead, 1940; Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Ordway Tead, 1931; Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Ordway Tead, 1988-1991; Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 5)
- XIX. Health Insurance, 1920; Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Ordway Tead, Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Ordway Tead - A Universal Reign of Law, Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Ordway Tead - A Universal Reign of Law, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Ordway Tead - A Universal Reign of Law, 1951; Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Ordway Tead - Universal Reign of Law, 1946; Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Ordway Tead - The Place of Philosophy in Postwar Education, 1944; Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Fromm, Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Speeches - Outlines of Meaning of Culture, 1955-1958; Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 14)
- What is Education?, Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 15)
- A Vain Thing for Safety, Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 16)
- The Rich Miss Brown, Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Federal Reserve 17 - Course, Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 18)
- The Cooperative Association, Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 19)
- The Industrial Audit, Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Basis of Capitalization 17 - Course, 1927-1939; Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Misc., Black and white photograph (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Ordway Tead - Teaching, Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Ordway Tead - College Commencements, 1947; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Ordway Tead, 1967; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Living as a Fine Art, Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Administration in International Action, 1945; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 5)
- 'The Commitment of the College Teacher - To What and Why?' Ordway Tead, Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 6)
- The Meeting at Bandung - Diana Tead, 1946; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Basic Educational Provisions for the Two Year College, 1960; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Behind the Faade, Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Briarcliff Alumnae Day - After Briarcliff What 5/2/59, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Things Unseen Eternal BC Chapel 1958, Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Speeches BJC Commencement and Otherwise, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Briarcliff college - Convocations (1957-1958), Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Speeches BJC Convocations, 1952-1955; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Speeches BJC Faculty Topics, 1947; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Briarcliff Addresses, 1949; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Bridging the Gulf Between Liberal and Vocational, 1946; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Broader Mandate for Higher Education, Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Business Leadership in the Decade Ahead, 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Challenge of Education to Women, 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Character Building and Higher Education, 1952; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Character Building and Higher Education (Richmond forum 1957), Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Character of the College Teacher, 1967; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Charter for a College, 1939; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Speeches City College, 1952; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 25)
- City College Inauguration - 1953, Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Clear Thinking as a College a IM (U of Richmond 1957), Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Comments on Climate of Learning, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Pagans or Committed Citizens, 1958; Black and white photograph (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Colby College Report, 1954; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Speeches Ideas and Clippings, 1941; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Columbia Teaching Course, 1947; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 3)
- The College and Character Education (Unpublished), Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 4)
- College's Continuing Intellectual and Moral Affirmation - Wesleyan, 1954; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 5)
- College Education and Character ????????????????????????????????????? College Education and Character, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 6)
- College Learning and Teaching Reexamined, Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 7)
- College Education and Contemporary Understanding, 1964; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 8)
- The College Teacher and his at Syracuse, 1957, Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 9)
- College Teaching and College Learning, 1956; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 10)
- College Teaching in the First Two Years Speech: Redlands, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 11)
- College Teaching: An Adventure Vocation, 1957; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 12)
- College Teaching as a Spiritual Adventure, 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 13)
- College Teaching as Helped to Effectiveness Through Knowledge of Learning Process Albion College, 1954; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Some Questions on College Teaching, 1954; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 15)
- College Trustees - Their Opportunities and Duties, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 16)
- College Walls and College Bridges, 1953; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 17)
- The Community College Looks Ahead, 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Coping with Life, Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 19)
- The Courage to be Yourself BJC Convocation, 1955; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Courage to Face the Unforeseen, 1952; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Creating Dynamic Teacher Leadership, 1959; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Creative Writing, Secrets of, Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Crisis in American Education, 1951; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Current Developments in Industrial Relations, 1957; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Curricular Problems of Today and Tomorrow (Hamilton), 1950; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Curriculum for What?, 1949; Black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Ethics in Business Cong (Church), Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Democracy and Religion a Note, 1957; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Design for Living, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Developing Spiritual Insights, 1945; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Economic Channeling of Personal Power, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Employee Morale in Food Serving Agencies, 1941; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Democratic Leadership in Management, 1951; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Address at Executive Leadership Institute - U.S. Civil Service Commission January, 6, 1961; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Educated Man Faces the Unforeseen, 1948; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Speeches - Education, 1946; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Education for Character, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Democracy and Leadership in Education (The Smith Club and the Spence School), Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Creative Personality: A Challenge for Managers, 1940; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Employee Counseling: A New Personnel Assignment - it's Status and Standards, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Education for Self and Society, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Education for Social Well-Being, 1948; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Education for World Mindedness, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Education in a Post War World, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Education in the Public Interest, 1946; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Effective Learning in College with Special Reference to Natural Sciences, 1952; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 20)
- John L. Elliott, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Executive Leadership - What is it?, 1951-1952; Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Emma Willard, Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Engineering Education as a Moral Adventure (Okla 1956), Black and white photograph (Box 9, Folder 24)